原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     小酸奶  Silence  我有猫我骄傲
翻译     学术男优  一只虾  DustD
校对     苏小黛
时间轴     啾啾  大葱
后期     8T
总监     苏小黛
前情提要
-你干了什么  凯蒂  -都结束了  所以不重要了
- What have you done, Katy? - It's over, so it doesn't matter.
别走
Please don't Leave!
发生什么事了
What happened?
你还是问问你老婆吧
Why don't you ask your wife?
你是相信我的  对吧
You do believe me, don't you?
你相信我绝不会做出那样的事
You believe that I couldn't do something Like that?
当然  我相信你
Yeah. Course I do.
我就是个垃圾收集者  我什么也改变不了
I'm just a rubbish collector. I don't change anything.
我只能清理那些垃圾
I just sweep up the crap
而第二天它们又出现了
and the next day it's all just there again.
你做的事是重要的  它可以改变人们的生活
What you do is important. It makes a difference to people.
也是我当初爱上你的原因之一
It's one of the reasons I fell for you in the first place.
我只在乎他要对自己的行为负责任
All I care about is him answering for what he's done.
他们会找到证据  证明你强奸了我
They're gonna find proof that you raped me!
不  不会的  警探  不会的
No, you won't, Detective. No, you won't.
谁在撒谎
第一季第六集[本季终]
爸爸  怎么了
Dad? What's going on?
对不起  我没想把你吵醒的
Ah, I'm sorry, mate. I didn't mean to wake you up.
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
我告诉你也不会信的
You won't believe me if I told you.
这不重要
It's not important.
不过你只要知道
All you need to know is, though, er...
还没有结束
it's not over.
-什么  -警察
- What? - The police.
我不明白  他们就是不肯放过我
I don't understand it, they just won't let it lie.
你的老师对我
It wasn't enough that your teacher
提出那种指控还不够  现在警探...
made all those accusations against me, now the detective...
爸爸  出什么事了
Dad, what's going on?
警探也指控我
The detective is accusing me, too.
她说我攻击了她
She's saying that I attacked her.
她说几天前晚上
She's saying that a couple of nights ago
我闯进了她家
I broke into her house.
那太疯狂了
That's crazy. I mean,
你已经证明尼尔森老师之前也撒过谎...
You already proved that Miss Nielson was lying before...
人们不能就这样乱泼脏水  爸爸
People can't just go around saying this stuff, Dad.
这样不对  告诉她上级
It's not right. Just tell her boss.
肯定有人能阻止这一切的
There must be someone who can make this stop.
警察只会护着自己人
The police, you see, they look after their own.
他们就是这样
That's how they work.
不管她怎么说  他们都会信
Whatever she says, they'll back her up.
我们两人只能各执一词
It's just her word against mine.
我完蛋了
And I'll be destroyed.
除非
Unless er...
不知道  如果...也许如果
I don't know. What er... What if maybe er...
你告诉他们你看到过我
you told them that you saw me?
你想让我对警察撒谎
You want me to lie to the police?
不不不  天啊  不是那样的
No, no, no. God, nothing like that.
只是
Just erm...
我需要你的帮助  就像我
I need your help. You know, in the same way
帮你对付马可达的爸爸那样
that I helped you with Makeda's father?
那种善意的谎言
The kind of lie that's a good lie?
伙计
Look, mate...
我很不想这样要你帮忙  好吗
I feel sick to my stomach asking you, all right?
可我很害怕
But I'm afraid.
老实说  伙计  我真的很怕
To be honest with you, mate, I'm really scared.
他们要弄死我...
They want blood and...
他们...他们完全不会罢休
..They'll... they won't stop at anything.
天啊  如果我保护不了自己  谁来保护你
Christ, if I can't protect myself, who's gonna protect you?
天啊  对不起
Oh, God. I'm so sorry.
对不起  忘了我刚说的一切  好吗
I'm so sorry, just forget that I asked, 0K?
忘了我的请求
Forget that I asked.
太尴尬了  原谅我
I'm so embarrassed. Please forgive me.
对不起那样要求你  忘了吧
I'm so sorry that I asked, 0K? Just forget about it.
我到底怎么了  我都没法...
Christ, what's happening to me? I can't even...
不管你需要什么  爸爸
Whatever you need, Dad.
不管你需要什么  我都会告诉他们
I'll tell them whatever you need.
我不会让他们这么对你的
I'm not gonna let them do this to you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
天啊  谢谢你
Oh, my God, thank you.
谢谢你  伙计
Thanks, mate.
你为什么觉得这次会不一样
What makes you think it'll be different this time?
你为什么觉得你能把他抓起来
What makes you think you can put him away?
让我来操心安德鲁·厄拉姆的事
You need to let me worry about Andrew Earlham.
-等你...  -等我们提出指控就给你电话
- Will you call me as soon as you - As soon as we press charges.
我保证
I promise.
好的
Ok.
三个月后
-旅途怎么样  -很不错  谢谢
- How was the journey down? - Good. Really easy. Thanks.
-你应该让我来找你的  -不不不
- You really should have let me come to you. - Oh, no, no, no.
这里很不错  我一直很想来这里
This is nice. I always wanted to come here.
你看上去不错
You look good.
不是说你平时看上去不好
Not that you don't always look good.
谢谢
Thanks.
喝的
OK. Er, drinks.
你想喝点什么
What can I get you?
我去拿吧  如果你不介意的话
Actually, I'll get them, if you don't mind.
拜托  让我去吧
Please. Let me.
好的
Ok.
去吧  跑跑跑跑跑
Go on. Run, run, run, run.
快跑
Run!
不不  你们别动
No, no, you're staying there.
孩子们来了  玩得开心吗
Yeah, there's my boys. Did you have a good time?
你们玩得开心吗
Did you have fun?
去吧  我烧好茶了
Go on, I've got tea ready for you.
我马上就来
I'll be with you in a second.
他们一直问我会不会留下来
So they kept asking if I was going to stay.
是啊...
Well, it's er...
他们可能需要点时间习惯
it's gonna take some time for them to get used to it.
但他们会习惯的
But they will.
他们没必要习惯
They don't have to.
是你的错  凯蒂
You did this, Katy.
-不关别人的事  -我只想求你
- No-one else. - All I'm asking
我们为了他们试试
is that we try, for them.
我不想让他们在成长的过程中
I don't want them growing
被我们两边拖拽
up being pulled in two different directions,
-夹在中间  -我也不想那样
- caught in the middle - And I don't want that either.
但你的所作所为
But what you did...
我没法忘记
I can't forget that.
也没法原谅
Or forgive it.
爸爸来了
Daddy's coming.
周二见
See you on Tuesday.
我在地铁上  给一位女士让了座
So I was on the Tube and I offered my seat to this, erm, lady,
她问  为什么
and she said, 'Why?'
我说  因为你怀孕了
And I said, 'Well, because you're pregnant.'
-她说  我没有怀孕  -天啊
- And she said, 'l'm not pregnant.' - Oh, my God.
-你说了什么  -我想不到该说什么
- What did you say? - I couldn't think of anything to say.
她看上去就像怀孕了
I mean, she looked pregnant.
肚子的形状
From the shape of it.
我本来很确定...
l was really sure...
也许她只会觉得你很绅士
Maybe she just thought you were being chivalrous.
让座给一个胖子吗
By offering my seat to a fat person?
所以现在我只要在车上看到有人站着
So now whenever I'm on a train and I see someone standing,
我脑中就会浮现出无数想法
l have a million thoughts going through my head.
她们真的是怀孕了吗  他们是不是没那么老
Are they not actually pregnant? Are they not that old?
她们是不是女的
Are they not even a woman?
简直是个雷区
It's a minefield.
这也太不公平了
It's not fair, though, is it?
你只是想做点好事  然后...
You were just trying to do something nice and...
怎么了  怎么回事
What? What is it?
怎么了  那是谁
What is it? Who is that?
劳拉  是他吗
Laura, is that him?
这不重要
It doesn't matter.
天啊
Jesus.
他被二次调查了  对吗
He was investigated a second time, right?
警察把他的生活翻了个底朝天  什么都没发现
Police turned his life upside down and found precisely nothing.
他们就把他放了吗
They just let him go?
就算哈蒙警长指控了他
Even after DI Harmon's charges,
他们也找不到抓他的证据
they couldn't find anything to put him away.
我想是因为他知道怎么销毁证据吧
He knows how to cover his tracks, I suppose.
难以想象你看到他这样逍遥法外的感受
I can't imagine what it must feel like to see him walking around.
我愤怒了很久  但是...
Well, I've been angry for long time, but erm...
这会消耗你
it wastes you.
会把你吞噬掉
It eats away at you and erm...
每当我有这种感觉时
Every time I feel that way,
感觉就像是事情再一次发生
it's like it's happening all over again,
所以在某一刻  不得不放手
so at some point you have to... let it go or...
或者至少试一试
try to, at least.
这杯敬你
Here's to you.
-还有多久  -一个月
- So how much longer? - A month.
-你找到新地方了吗  -没 很理智吧
- Have you found a new place yet? - No. Sensible, hey?
我只是觉得
I just felt like
离开这个鬼地方是当务之急
getting the hell out of this place was the priority,
但我看的所有房子
but everything I look at,
都不太好  要么太小  要么离公路太近
all I see is the bad stuff too small, too close to a road.
有个房子颜色太黄了
One place was too yellow.
那真不能要
That's a deal breaker.
谢谢你让我过了一个愉快的夜晚
Thanks for a lovely night.
真的很高兴跟你见面
Yeah, it was... it was really good seeing you.
抱歉  你一路送我回来
I'm sorry. You've come all this way
-而我却不请你进屋  -不不  没事
- and I'm not even inviting you in. - No, no, not at all.
那下周见
See you next week?
下周见
Next week it is.
晚安  伊恩
Good night, Ian.
晚安  劳拉
Good night, Laura.
就喝一杯  街角就有家很棒的小酒吧
One drink. There's a beautiful little pub just round the corner.
你现在已经和我约会这么多次了
You've been on enough dates with me now.
你觉得我这么容易被说服吗
Do you think I'm easily persuaded?
至少我试了
At least I tried.
但下次吃晚饭  我坚持由我来做饭
But next time, dinner, I'll cook, I insist.
如果我做瑞士千层酥皮鲑鱼
If I make my salmon en croute,
也许我儿子就会走开
maybe my son will bugger off.
也许我们就能单独相处一会
We might have a moment to ourselves.
-那好吧  -太好了
- All right, then. - Yes.
晚安
Good night.
好了  晚安
OK, good night.
下次见
Till next time.
夏洛特  你好
Charlotte? Hi.
我叫劳拉·尼尔森
I'm Laura Nielson.
感谢你能来
I appreciate you coming.
你应该知道安德鲁和我说起过你
You should know Andrew told me about you.
他怎么说的
What did he say exactly?
我第一次见他时  他就跟我说了
He told me, the first time I met him,
关于你给他带来的那些麻烦
about all the trouble you'd caused him.
在那之后  他删除了所有社交媒体账号
He deleted all of his social media accounts after that,
用别名注册了一个新账户
set up a new one under an alias
结果你还是找到了他
and yet you still found him.
还有我
And me.
我应该防着你吗
Should I be worried about you?
安德鲁·厄拉姆强奸了我
Andrew Earlham raped me.
强奸了一位名叫凡妮莎·哈蒙的警探
He raped a police officer called Vanessa Harmon,
在爱丁堡强奸了一位叫凯瑟琳·麦考利的女子
and he raped a woman called Catherine MacAulay in Edinburgh.
这是她们的号码
Here are their numbers.
如果你不相信我  那就跟她们聊聊吧
If you don't believe me, then talk to them.
然后再作出判断  你觉得谁说的是真话
Then you make up your mind who you think is telling the truth,
是我们三人  还是安德鲁
the three of us or Andrew.
我不认识你  但是我知道他
Look, I don't know you, but I know him,
我知道他能做出些什么事
and I know what he's capable of.
他喜欢聪慧  独立
He likes women who are smart, independent,
更有挑战的女人
more of a challenge to control.
但愿你够聪明  能多留点神
I'm hoping you're smart enough to watch your back.
或者至少
Or at least...
够聪明地自己去查一查我跟你说的事
smart enough to check out what I'm telling you for yourself.
她真美
Aw. She's gorgeous.
-是吗  -她甚至有你那种能看穿人的头脑
- Is she? - Yeah, look, she's even got your see-through head.
如果是女孩的话
That's if she is a she.
你还好吧
Are you all right?
还好  我只是
Yeah, I'm just...
心不在焉
miles away.
我回来后  你一直这样
You have been since I got back.
还有一次出差任务
Look, it's... it's one more tour of duty,
然后我就能回家了  不再是珍妮佛大兵了
and then I'm home, right? No more GI Jennifer.
分娩之前我会回来的  然后我哪也不去了
I'll be back before the birth and then I'm not going anywhere.
我只是想你了
Yeah. I just miss you, that's all.
你骗不了我  妮莎
You can't lie to me, Ness.
发生什么事了  你一脸愁容
What's going on? You've got that look.
-没事  -听着
- It's nothing. - Look,
我可以一直问到你受不了为止
I can keep asking you, again and again till I drive you crazy
或者你现在就告诉我
or you can just tell me now.
别问了  好吗  我没事
Just leave it, OK, I am fine.
你就告诉我吧
Just tell me.
妮莎
Ness...
你变了
you've changed.
你努力想要掩盖  但是
You've tried to pretend, but...
但我知道
but I know what...
我只是想要听实话
All I'm asking for is the truth.
是有其他人吗
Is there someone else?
天  不是的  当然不是
God, no. Of course not.
那  到底怎么回事
Well, then, what is it?
你走的这些天里  发生了一些事  但拜托
While you were away, something happened, but please...
我不能  我不想说出口
please, I can't, I don't want to say it out loud.
不管是什么事  都没事的
Whatever it is, it's OK.
你可以告诉我  怎么回事
You can tell me. You can tell me, what is it?
发生什么了
What is it?
告诉我
Just tell me.
卢克
Luke?
伙计
Hey, mate.
-你怎么样  -挺好
- How are you doing? - Fine.
那就好
Good.
很好
That's good.
我想问问
I was wondering...
在学校还好吗
..How's school, eh?
只是撤销了指控
Just because the charges were dropped,
并不意味着人们不再讨论了  是吧
doesn't mean people don't talk, right?
我知道这对你来说有多不难  但你这样并不能
I know how hard it is for you but it's not gonna get any easier -
别给我什么建议了  爸爸
Spare me the advice, Dad.
就好像你有资格说这些话一样
Like you're in any position.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你这话什么意思  卢克
What does that mean? Luke?
我洗清了罪名
I was cleared.
所有的罪名都洗得干干净净
All those charges, not one of them stuck.
要是你不相信我  好吧  你和我
If you don't believe me, right, you and me...
要是你
If you...
夏洛特  你好吗
Charlotte. Hey. How are you?
慢点说  慢点说
Slow down, slow down.
什么
What?
她说了什么
What did she say?
安德鲁·厄拉姆
你想怎样
What do you want?
我想谈谈  劳拉  我还能想干什么
'I want to talk, Laura. What else would I want?'
你离我远点
You need to leave me alone.
现在睡觉有点早  不是吗
'Bit early to be in bed, isn't it?'
你说什么
What did you say?
你会想我吗  当你躺在那的时候
'Do you think about me? When you're lying there.'
你肯定想起我了  不是吗  尽管你不会承认
'You do, don't you? Even though you wouldn't admit it.'
你现在立刻给我离开这里
You need to get away from here right now.
我知道你和夏洛特聊过
'I know you spoke to Charlotte,
而且我觉得你才是那个该滚开的人
and I think you're the one that needs to back off.
我们是时候继续自己的生活了  你不觉得吗
Time we both got on with our lives, don't you think?'
你觉得你凌驾于所有人和事  是吗
You think you stand above everyone and everything, don't you?
你觉得没人抓得到你
That you're untouchable.
但你也只是个人罢了  安德鲁
But you're just a man, Andrew.
一个恶心脆弱的人
A sick, weak man.
总有一天你会清醒过来
And one day you're gonna wake up
你造成的所有痛苦都将报复到你身上来
and all the pain you've caused is just gonna come back on you.
你听起来很害怕  别怕
You sound scared. Don't be.
因为如果我想占有你
Cos if I wanted to have you...
再次占有你
again...
你不觉得只要我想  随时都能动手吗
don't you think I could have had you whenever I wanted?
-我要报警了  -你有没有回想过那一晚
- I'm calling the police. - 'Do you ever think about that night?'
我知道我回想过
'I know I do.
有花朵图案的床单  粉红的枕套
The floral-patterned sheets, the pink pillowcases,
床上灰色的盖毯
the grey throw on the bed,
肯定是几周前刚换的
which couldn't have been more than a few weeks old.
其中一个商标
One of the tags was still
还挂在右下角
hanging from the bottom right-hand corner.
而你...躺在那儿
And you...lying there.
任由我摆布
Letting me do whatever I wanted.
我只要有机会就会重播  劳拉
I play that back, Laura, whenever I get the chance
好了  再见
All right, I'll see you soon.
-劳拉  -安德鲁昨晚出现在了我家外面
- Laura? - Andrew turned up outside my house last night.
-什么  -是啊  但他什么都没做
- What? - Yeah, he didn't do anything.
他只是想恐吓我  而且他做到了
He just wanted to scare me, and it worked.
我整晚都没睡
I couldn't sleep all night.
好的
OK.
我认为他把我们录下来了
I think he filmed us.
他对我们做的那些事
What he did to us.
为什么这么说
Why would you say that?
他谈到了那晚  谈到了...
He talked about that night. He talked about erm...
墙上的一幅画
a picture on my wall...
我床上很小的细节  那些琐碎的小事
some tiny detail about my bed, little things...
他当时在我房间里不可能注意到那些
that he couldn't have noticed in the time he was in my room.
-他有时间四周打探  -他说...
- He had time to look around. - He said...
"我只要有机会就会重播"
"I play that back whenever I get the chance."
不是「我会回想」  而是「我会重播」
Not "I think about it", "I play it back."
可能只是一种说法
Could just be an expression.
他说的那些事  那些细节
The things he said, the detail he went into.
我跟你说  他都录下来了
I'm telling you, he recorded it
而且那个令人作呕的杂种把证据藏在某处
and the sick bastard still has it somewhere.
劳拉...
Laura...
他那样的男人就是想控制和羞辱女性
Men like him want to control and humiliate women.
还有什么比录下来更羞辱人的
What's more humiliating than a recording?
别说了  我们搜过他的家  工作地还有电脑
Stop. We searched his house, his work, his computer.
以及他的所有电子设备  好吗
Every electronic device he has, OK?
-我们什么都没找着  -我知道
- And we found nothing. - I know.
但他太狡猾了
But he's too smart for that.
劳拉  我需要你
Laura, what I need you to do
什么都不要去做  好吗
is absolutely nothing, OK?
我可以派一辆巡逻警车守在你家外面
Now, I can get a patrol car to stay outside your house.
真棒  我所有问题都解决了
Great, all my problems are solved
听着  你能至少把我说的那些话
Look, will you pass on what I've said at least?
转达给你的那个同事吗  只是...
To your colleagues. Just...
现在和他在一起的那个女人  夏洛特
That woman he's with now, Charlotte,
我希望她平安无事
I want her to be all right.
好的  我会跟他说的
Yeah, sure, I'll pass it on.
-你好  警探  -凡妮莎
- Hi, Detective - Vanessa.
-抱歉打扰了  -没事  只是在赶些文书
- Sorry to bother you. - No bother. I'm catching up on paperwork.
我刚刚和劳拉·尼尔森通过电话了
I just spoke with Laura Nielson.
劳拉  我昨天见到她了
Laura, yeah, I met her yesterday.
她认为安德鲁·厄拉姆录下了他的罪行
She thinks Andrew Earlham records his attacks.
他把东西藏在了某个地方
That he's storing them somewhere.
厄拉姆昨晚出现在了她家外面
Earlham turned up outside her house last night.
他发现了她正在调查他
He found out she's been looking into him.
我知道
I know.
因为你告诉他的  为什么
Because you told him? Why?
我们要让安德鲁坐立不安  愤怒
We need Andrew unsettled. Angry.
那样他就会犯错  我们就可以把他绳之以法
That's when he'll make mistakes, that's when we'll catch him.
别担心  我们在劳拉住的地方安排了巡逻车
Don't worry, we had a squad car on Laura's place.
你不应该让她掺和进来的
You shouldn't put her in the middle of this.
是她自己掺和进来的
She put herself in the middle.
我只是抓住了机会给安德鲁施压
I just took the opportunity to push Andrew.
-抱歉  我知道我没发言权  -你当然有
- I'm sorry, I know this isn't my place, but - Course it is.
这项行动多亏了你
This operation is down to you.
我只是希望能有更多证据上报
I just wish we had more to report.
-但今晚我要去他家吃完饭  -今晚
- But tonight I'm going for dinner at his place. - Tonight?
美妙周五夜  是吧
Great Friday night, huh
记住  别让自己有机可乘
Remember, don't make yourself too available.
我看过资料了
I've read the profile.
-我只是提醒你  因为...  -我知道
- I'm only saying because... - Look, I know
等着批准通过很让人泄气
how frustrating it's been waiting for approval to come through
但我们成功在望了  有点信心
but we're close now. Just keep the faith.
好的
Ok.
-谢谢  警探  -没事
- Thanks, Detective. - Of course.
-马上就好  -我们需要你去五号检查室
- Yep, just a minute. - OK, we need you in Exam 5.
我能先从柜子里拿点东西出来吗
Can I grab something from my locker?
没时间了  他们早就在等着了
There isn't much time. They've been waiting already.
好吧  咱们去把这个处理完
All right, then, let's get this over with.
很高兴你给我打了电话
I'm glad you called.
我们好久都没联系了
It's been a long time.
是啊
Yeah.
给你
Er, here.
安德鲁的手机
Andrew's phone.
谢谢
Thank you.
我会为你做任何事  你知道的
I'd do anything for you, you know that.
虽然你还在生我的气
Even when you're angry at me.
我猜你也不会告诉我要这手机干什么
I don't suppose you're gonna tell me what that's for?
-你最好不要知道  -不要知道
- It's probably best that you don't know. - Don't know.
没事
Ok.
我以为你已经释怀了  劳拉
I thought you were moving on with your life, Laura.
-我必须这么做  -不  你不需要
- I have to do this. - No, you don't.
你从来都不需要做这些事
You never had to do any of it.
你经历了噩梦般的事  你一直想纠正
You had a terrible thing happen to you and you tried to fix it.
而不是给自己点时间来恢复
Instead of taking time to get better and look after yourself.
我很想你
I miss you.
我也想你
I miss you, too.
你觉得你会停止恨我吗
Do you think you'll ever stop hating me?
我并不恨你  凯蒂
I don't hate you, Katy.
我只是...我没法再相信你了
I just... I can't trust you.
我也不知道要怎么面对你
And I don't know how to be around you.
好吧...
Well...
等你准备好了
when you are ready...
...你知道我在哪
..You know where I am.
-快请进  -你好
- Hi, come in, come in. - Hey.
-谢谢  -就挂这吧
- Thanks. - There you go. Thank you.
你真美
Wow, you look amazing.
-从这里过去就好  -赞
- Just through here. - Great.
-挺香的啊  -谢谢夸奖
- That smells good. - Thank you.
也没什么特别  就是一些专门订购的食材
It's nothing much, just er, speciality-ordered ingredients
还为此准备了两天
and about 48 hours of preparation.
-我很高兴你能来  -为何不来
- I'm glad you came. - Why wouldn't I?
今天有人从我柜子里拿走了我的手机
Someone took my phone from a locker today.
-真烦人  -没事  我把那个号取消了
- That's annoying. - No, it's fine, it's been cancelled,
我订了另一支手机
and there's another one ordered.
你懂的  没了手机就好像成了孩子
You know how it is - you lose your phone, you feel like a child.
不能发短信取消或修改时间
How did we ever make social arrangements
那我们要怎么约人
when we couldn't cancel or change with a text last-minute?
我只要答应了就会出现
Well, I like to turn up when I've agreed to.
我就是那么老套
I'm old-fashioned like that.
我也是
Me, too.
来点酒吗  女士
Drink, m'lady?
好啊  听起来不错
Yeah. Sounds good.
-你这地方挺不错的  -谢谢  还行吧
- I like your place. - Thanks. It's OK.
我一直想买些画挂墙上  你知道吗
Keep meaning to buy some more art to put on the walls, you know?
其实我上周买到了心仪的  是个本地的艺术家
I found something last week, actually. A local artist.
就在隔壁房的墙上  你有兴趣可以去看看
It's on the wall in the other room, if you fancy.
当然
Sure.
冒昧问一下
Forgive me for asking. Er...
你还好吗
Are you okay?
-当然  怎么了  -我不知道
- Of course. Why? - Oh, I don't know.
你...你有点不自在
You just... You seem tense.
有点累吧
Long day.
那我正好有你需要的东西
Then I have just the thing for you.
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
抱歉  我能要杯水吗  今天有点脱水
Sorry, could I get a glass of water? I'm a bit dehydrated today.
我不想让你误会
I don't want to start off on the wrong foot.
没事  我马上来
Yes, yes, of course. I'll be right back.
-给你  -谢谢
- There you go. - Thanks.
这画真不错  作者叫什么
It's a nice piece. What's the artist's name?
你包里的是什么  夏洛特
What's in your bag, Charlotte?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我看到你了
I saw you.
你看到我干什么  我不太懂
You saw me what? I don't understand.
你用注射器抽取了红酒
You filled a syringe from your glass.
然后
And then...
我猜  你会编借口吧
You'll be making your excuses, I imagine.
一个紧急电话打来  然后你要先离开
An urgent phone call that meant you just had to leave
或者忽然头很痛  然后...
or a sudden headache and then...
然后干什么呢
and then what?
把这珍贵的样本送去警察实验室吗
Take your precious sample down to the police lab?
是这样吗
Is that about the size of it?
夏洛特
Charlotte?
让开
Step away.
为什么
Why?
你觉得我会对你做什么
What is it you think I'm gonna do to you?
我可以立刻叫来后援
I can have back-up here in seconds.
我可没阻止你离开
Well, I'm not stopping you from leaving.
你的实验室不会发现任何东西的
Your lab's not gonna find anything.
我给你倒了杯红酒  仅此而已
I poured you a glass of wine. And that's it.
真是可惜
It's a shame, really.
我们本可以很开心的
We'd have had fun.
我知道的
I know it.
该死  该死
Shit. Shit.
该死
Shit!
那么  这是什么原理
So, how does this work?
说实话  不知道
Honestly, no idea.
我技术小组的一个朋友给了我程序
A friend of mine from the tech squad just gave me the programme.
那你为什么要拿他的手机  为什么是现在
So, why did you take his phone, why now?
我觉得...
I think that erm...
当他强奸女人时候他会拍下来
when he rapes women he films it.
-你怎么知道的  -他说了一些话
- How do you know? - Something he said.
变态混蛋
Sick bastard.
我有机会的时候就该砸烂他的脸
I should've smashed his face in when I had the chance.
无论他把文件藏哪  都不在他家里
Wherever he keeps the files, they're not in his house,
也不在他的电脑和手机里
they're not on his computer or his phone,
警察肯定在哈蒙警长控告之后搜过了
the police would have searched after DI Harmon's charge.
所以如果他有记录  多半在其他地方
So if he keeps recordings, they're offsite?
他这种人  肯定会很小心
Someone like him, he will be careful.
会有很多要梳理的东西
There'll be a lot to get through.
我可以把手机的内容传到电脑上
I could dump the contents of the phone onto the laptop.
-我们可以一起看  -我知道我不该请你帮忙
- we can both look. - I know I shouldn't be asking you for help, it's...
上次就是因为帮助我才让你变成现在这样
helping me last time that got you into this situation.
别  是安德鲁最终害我丢了工作
Nah, Andrew was the one who made sure I lost my job.
好吧  那么...
Right. Well...
好  感谢你打电话来
OK. Thanks for calling.
行动不顺利
The op went badly.
针对安德鲁·厄拉姆的卧底行动
The undercover with Andrew Earlham.
有多遭
How bad?
天啊  没事的  我们会找到其他办法
Jesus. It's OK, we're gonna find another way.
怎么找
How?
他逃脱了上一个指控
He walked away from the last accusation.
现在是你  还需要多少人才能阻止他
And now you. How many more until somebody stops him?
我们在尽力  我是说  罗里
We're doing our best. I mean, Rory...
-整个团队  所有人  -显然还不够好
- the whole team, everybody. - Well, it's not good enough.
他在我们家里袭击了你  他需要面对后果
He attacked you in our house. He needs to face the consequences.
-冷静  珍  -我不能  这事...
- Calm down, Jen. - I can't. It's...
我知道事情发生在你身上而不是我
I know this happened to you and not me,
但我感觉保护你是我的职责
but I feel like it's my job to protect you,
-而我却没在  -请不要这么说  不要
- and I wasn't there. - Please don't say that. You mustn't.
珍
Jen.
安德鲁有没有提到过一个叫
Did Andrew ever mention anybody called...
-米娅·兰斯夫卡的人  -没有  怎么了
- Mia Lentzovka? - No. Why?
不知道呢  这里有个几天前的消息
Dunno. There's a text message from a few days ago.
所以警察肯定没看到
So the cops wouldn't have seen it.
「你什么时候能来拿你的东西」
"When can you come over to collect your things?"
有这个女人的地址吗
Is there an address for this woman?
-有  在联络簿里  -太好了  谢谢你
- Yeah, it's in the contacts. - Brilliant. Thank you.
好了  我要给凡妮莎打电话
Right. I'm gonna call Vanessa.
我希望这能有用
I hope it's useful.
谢谢
Thanks.
我真的很抱歉
I really am sorry.
关于我和凯蒂的事
About me and Katy.
我知道  我也是
I know. Me too.
谢谢你帮我
Thanks for helping me.
「你好  我是凡妮莎·哈蒙
'Hi, this is a Vanessa Harmon.
我现在不在  请留言」
I'm not around right now, so leave a message.
你好
Hello.
需要帮助吗
Can I help you?
你好  我是...
Hi, I'm a...
安德鲁的朋友
a friend of Andrew's.
安德鲁·厄拉姆
Andrew Earlham.
-他没事吧  -挺好的  他没事
- Is he all right? - Fine. Yeah, yeah, fine.
你是米娅吗
Erm, are you Mia?
是的  是我
Yes. I am.
我是劳拉
I'm Laura.
实际上  我能进去聊几分钟吗
Actually, is it all right if I come in for a minute?
谢谢
Thanks.
西尔维娅
Sylvia?
这是安德鲁的朋友  劳拉
This is a friend of Andrew's. Laura.
你好  亲爱的
Hello, dear.
能有访客真好
How nice to have a visitor.
安德鲁从来不带客人来  是吧  米娅
Andrew never brings visitors here, does he, Mia?
-从来没  -安德鲁叫我来帮他取东西
- No, never. - Andrew asked me to pick something up for him.
他有东西存在这里吗
He's got some stuff stored here?
他本应该几天前来拿的
He was supposed to collect it a few days ago.
是的
Yes.
是的  当然
Yes, of course.
请跟我来
Please, follow me.
谢谢
Thanks.
请吧
Here you go.
谢谢  我会尽量快点
Thanks. I'll try and be quick.
喂  我是米娅
Hello. It's Mia.
-你找到了吗  你有没有...  -有  谢谢
- Do you have everything? Did you find - Yes, thanks.
我得走了  谢谢你们
I've got to run. Thank you.
凡妮莎
-她在里边很生气  -好吧
- She's pretty upset in there. - OK.
-天啊  终于  -真抱歉
- Oh, God. Finally. - I'm sorry.
我没值班  我得走程序进来
I wasn't on duty. I had to get in.
我给凡妮莎打电话却直接进语音信息了
I called Vanessa but her phone goes straight to voicemail.
我还以为有了这发现  你们会行动快一些
You'd think people would move quicker after what I found.
前台告诉我录像的事了
The front desk told me about the recordings.
是啊  那个...
Yeah, it's erm...
是...
Yeah, erm...
我都没胆量去看  但是...
I could barely bring myself to look, but...
但我在里边  还有凡妮莎  还有...
But I'm in there, and...Vanessa and...
我算了算  至少还有其他15个人
I counted at least 15 others.
15位和我有同样遭遇的女人
15 women just like me.
17.
技术人员说是17位
The tech guys tell me 17.
而且安德鲁·厄拉姆可以很清晰地被辨认出
And Andrew Earlham is clearly identifiable.
他将会进去很长时间  尼尔森小姐
He's going away, Miss Nielson, for a really, really long time.
我之前也听过这话
I've heard that before.
他们让你进了房子  他们让你搜索小屋
They let you into the house. They let you search the shed.
你找到的一切都会成为证据
Everything you found is going into evidence.
我向你保证
I promise you.
已经结束了
It's over now.
结束了
It's over.
我们现在正去抓捕他
We're picking him up right now.
我们要找安德鲁·厄拉姆
We're looking for Andrew Earlham.
-找我爸爸干什么  -我们有逮捕令
- What do you want with my dad? - We have a warrant for his arrest.
他不在这里
He's not here.
强奸嫌疑犯
警察寻求帮助寻找肯特强奸嫌疑犯
最后  虽然进行了三周的搜寻
'And, finally, despite three weeks of searching,
警察依然无法找到安德鲁·厄拉姆
the police are no closer to finding Andrew Earlham,
此人与多项强奸指控有关
who is wanted in connection with a number of rape allegations.
厄拉姆先生  广山医院的心胸外科医生
Mr Earlham, a cardiothoracic surgeon at Broadhill Hospital,
是近几个月
has been the subject of
两起调查的主要对象
two separate investigations in recent months,
但是都没有最终定罪
but neither case led to prosecution.
几周前发布了一张针对厄拉姆先生的逮捕令
'Several weeks ago, a warrant was issued for Mr Earlham's arrest
之后不久  他几年前性侵对象的录像
and, shortly after, recordings of his alleged sexual assaults
被泄露给了媒体
dating back years, were leaked to the press.
警方寻求任何线索 只要关于厄拉姆先生
'Police ask that anyone with information on Mr Earlham
或是他目前的所在
or his whereabouts come forward.'